FABRIZIO CAMPO

Birmingham, Selly Oak, 266 Heeley Road, B29 6EN +44 7517621436 Fxc866@student.bham.ac.uk

LinkedIn: Fabrizio Campo

PROFILE

A determined and highly motivated Computer Science student with an interest in Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering and Data Science.

I started developing a passion for computer science since middle school when I took part in a National Robotics Competition. I am working hard on my degree program because I want to take a year out to gain industry experience. I want to satisfy my need for knowledge to enhance my career and contribute to technological innovation in the future.

EDUCATION

University of Birmingham, UK

September 2018 – Present

Bsc Artificial Intelligence and Computer Science

- 1st Year Modules:
 - Artificial Intelligence, Programming in Java, Data Structures and Algorithms, Logic and Computation, Mathematical Foundations of Computer Science.
 - Artificial Intelligence Project Robotics:
 - o Building and programming a Lego Mindstorms EV3 Robot in Java.
 - Programming an autonomous robot that follow a black line while overcoming different problems in a modular arena formed by tiles with different patterns and obstacles.
 - Programming an autonomous robot that explores and maps a maze, also able to find the best way-back to the start point once it reaches the end.
- 2nd Year Modules:
 - Software Engineering, Security and Network, Advanced Functional Programming,
 Mathematical Modelling and Decision Making, Systems Programming in C/C++, Artificial Intelligence Team Project.

University of Catania, IT

September 2017 – July 2018

1st Year of a Bsc Business Economics, Business Administration and Management

Activities and Societies:

- Member of a Student Union.
- Coordination, Management and Supervision of university activities.

Modules:

 Mathematics, Business Enterprise, Microeconomics, Accounting and Financial Statement, Economics History.

"Concetto Marchesi" Scientific High School

Scientific High School Diploma with 95/100.

- Italian (First Language) 14/15.
- Mathematics 14/15.
- Physics, Biology and Chemistry, English 14/15.

"Mario Pluchinotta" Middle School

2009 - 2012

Activities and Extra-Curricular course

- Class President.
- Organization of events.
- Robotics course and competition.

EXPERIENCE

Trigone Diving Catania – PADI 5 stars Diving Centre

March 2018 - August 2018

Professional Diving Centre in Acitrezza(CT)

June 2019 - August 2019

Professional Association of Diving Instructor(PADI)

PADI Divemaster

- Organizing, guiding and supervising recreational diving activities, both shore and boat based.
- Assisting instructors in conducting training programs and activities for certified divers.
- Assessing the Hazard of a dive site and informing divers of the hazards.
- Leading a group of divers in the water as a tour guide.
- Teach and certify skin divers and snorkellers.
- Diving session from boat usually four times a week(depends on weather condition).
- Managing group from 2 to 10 people.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACHIEVEMENTS

Start up Society 2018 - Present

- Learned entrepreneurial skills.
- Studied how to pitch a business.
- Took part in meeting about innovative and tech business.

Computer Science Society

2018 - Present

- Actively participated in quiz nights and tech talks.
- Assisted and helped other students having bugs and errors with their code.
- Doing workshop to improve programming skills.

Joining the Computer Science Society of the University of Birmingham is one of the most useful extracurricular activities. You find yourself involved in a friendly environment where students with a passion for computer science can enjoy sharing their knowledge and helping each other.

2012 - 2017

PADI Divemaster November 2017 - Present

I achieved this certification after years of training collecting other certificates that gradually took me from an amateur to a professional level.

<u>First Aid Certification(Emergency First Response)</u> - Cert.N 1708UV8358

2017 - Present

- Primary and Secondary Care
- Handling life-threatening emergencies
- Cardiopulmonary resuscitation
- Realistic scenario practice

This course taught me how to aid patients who aren't breathing, have any heartbeat, may have a spinal injury, being in shock or serious bleeding. Being prepared for these situations can really make the difference for someone's life wherever it happens.

National competition Robocup jr

December 2012 – January 2013

- Building and Programming a Lego Mindstorms NXT 2.0 with Scratch.
- Lead the school team.
- Gained the second position.

Having a leading role makes me understand a lot about the importance of roles in a team, about motivating all the team members in the positive moment but more importantly in tough ones. I learned how to work under pressure with time and space constraints and it was a great opportunity to apply problem-solving capability.

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Languages:

- Italian native speaker.
- Advanced English.

IT Skills:

- Programming in Java.
- Programming in C/C++.
- Programming in Python as a beginner

Soft Skills:

- Quick Learner.
- Able to Operate Under Pressure.
- Problem-solving and Decision Making.
- Multi-tasking.
- Organizational skills.
- Creativity and Innovation.

Interests:

Technology innovation, Scuba diving and Sports such as Rugby, Football and Athletics.

Windows and Linux.

 Proficient in Microsoft Office including Excel and PowerPoint.

- Self-Motivation.
- Teamwork.
- Leadership.